sidetour.com 2012-04-05

# Privacy Policy :: SideTour

**Date of Last Revision: August 4, 2011**

Welcome to SideTour!

Arootz Inc., a Delaware corporation (“SideTour”, “we”, “us” or “our”) maintains the website at http://www.sidetour.com (the “Site”) and provides related services (collectively, such services, including any new features and applications, and the Site, the “Services”) subject to the following Privacy Policy (as updated and amended from time to time, this “Privacy Policy”).

Your privacy is very important to us.  Accordingly, we have developed this Privacy Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate and disclose personal information.

Pursuant to SideTour’s Terms of Use located at www.sidetour.com/terms-of-use, you must be 18 years and older to use the Services. Therefore, this Privacy Policy makes no provision for individuals under 18 years old. ****

**1.        ****Information Collected and How it is Used**

1.1   Information That You Provide.  SideTour collects personal information from you when you voluntarily provide such information through the Services (e.g. when you choose to host or purchase an experience, utilize messaging services, register for newsletters or contact us with inquiries). This includes, but is not limited to, your name, email address, location and phone number but does not include your credit card number or billing information. All transactions are processed by Eventbrite or PayPal. No one sees your credit card information besides Eventbrite or Paypal, not even us. SideTour will not sell or disclose your name or email address to third parties without your explicit consent, except as specified in this Privacy Policy.  If you provide personal information for a certain reason, we may use the personal information in connection with the reason for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by email, we will use the personal information you provide to respond to your email or if you provide personal information in order to obtain access to the Services, we will use your personal information to provide you with access to such Services and to monitor your use of such Services.  SideTour may also use your personal information collected through the Site to help us improve the content and functionality of the Site, to better understand our users and to improve the Services.

1.2   Non-Identifiable or Aggregated Data.  When you interact with SideTour through the Services, SideTour automatically receives and records certain personally non-identifiable information, including your IP address, cookies and the pages you request. SideTour may store such information itself or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by SideTour affiliates, agents or service providers.  SideTour may use such information and pool it with other information to track, for example, the total number of visitors to the Site, the number of visitors to each page of the Site, the domain names of our visitors’ Internet service providers and how our users use and interact with the Services.  Also, in an ongoing effort to better understand and serve the users of the Services, SideTour often conducts research on its customer demographics, interests and behavior based on the personal information and other information provided to us.  This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis.  SideTour may share this non-identifiable and aggregate data with its affiliates, agents and business partners, but this type of non-identifiable and aggregate information does not identify you personally. SideTour may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe the Services to current and prospective business partners and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.

1.3   Cookies.  A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a website’s computers and stored on your computer’s hard drive.  When you visit the Site, we send one or more cookies to your computer or other device. We use cookies to improve the quality of the Services, including for storing user preferences and tracking user trends, such as how people search. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. We recommend that you leave cookies turned on because they allow you to take advantage of some of the Site’s features.

1.4   SideTour uses information for the following general purposes: products and services provisioning, billing, identification and authentication, services improvement, contact, research and anonymous reporting.

**2.        ****Service-related Announcements**

SideTour will send you a welcome/confirmation email when you sign up for the Services.  SideTour may use personal information to contact you to tell you about Services we believe will be of interest to you. If we do so, each communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to “opt-out” of receiving future communications. You may not opt-out of service-related communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account by emailing [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com) from the email address you signed up with. ****

**3.        ****Administrative Messages**

SideTour may periodically email you with administrative messages. If you do not wish to receive administrative messages, you may opt-out by emailing [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com).  Please note that if you do not wish to receive administrative messages from us, those notices will still govern your use of the Site and the Services, and you are responsible for reviewing such notices for changes. ****

**4.        ****Host Profile**

If you choose to host an experience, your profile, including your full name and bio, is displayed on the Site (and so available to the public) and is connected to all of your offered experiences. Any information you choose to provide as part of your profile should reflect how much you want other SideTour users to know about you. We recommend that you guard any sensitive information and we encourage users to think carefully about what information they disclose in their profile. You can revise your profile information at any time by contacting us at [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com).  Other people can see your experiences for sale, feedback, ratings and associated comments. ****

**5.        ****Friend Features**

“Tell a Friend” allows members to share information about a specific item listed on SideTour by sending a personalized email message. If you choose to use SideTour’s “Tell a Friend” feature, SideTour will ask for the information needed to send the message, such as your friend’s email address. SideTour will then automatically send your friend an email, inviting your friend to visit the site. SideTour does not store “Tell a Friend” information on our servers. Your friend may utilize the “unsubscribe” link in the email to opt-out of receiving future “Tell a Friend” emails from SideTour. ****

**6.        ****Restriction on Users’ Use of Personal Information**

As part of a transaction, you may obtain personal information, including email address, mailing address and phone number information, from another user. Without obtaining prior permission from the other user, this personal information shall only be used for that transaction or for SideTour-related communications. SideTour has not granted you a license to use the information for unsolicited commercial messages. Without limiting the foregoing, without express consent from the user, you are not licensed to add any SideTour user to your email or physical mail list. ****

**7.        ****Disclosure of Your Personal Information to Third Parties**

In certain circumstances, we may share your personal information with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below:

7.1   Other Users.  As part of a transaction, other user’s may obtain your personal information, including email address, mailing address and phone number information. You agree that such user may use your personal information only for that transaction or for SideTour-related communications.

7.2   Business Transfers.  As we develop our business, SideTour may choose to buy or sell assets or businesses. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, personal information may be part of the transferred assets. In such an event, SideTour will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on the Site before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

7.3   Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties.  SideTour sometimes hires other companies to perform certain business-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases and processing payments. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function.

7.4   Legal Requirements.  SideTour may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect or defend the rights or property of SideTour, (iii) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or the public, violations of SideTour’s Terms of Use, or (iv) protect against legal liability.

**8.        ****Editing and Deleting Account Information**

If your personally identifiable information changes, you may correct or update it by emailing [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com). You may delete or deactivate your account by emailing [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com). SideTour will respond to your request within 10-20 business days.  Please note that your identification, billing and contact information may remain in SideTour’s records for some period. ****

**9.        ****Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us.  SideTour takes reasonable steps to protect the personal information submitted to us via the Site, both during transmission and once SideTour receives it.  SideTour limits access to personal information about you to employees who SideTour believes reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.  Personal information is password-protected.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, SideTour cannot guarantee absolute security of your personal information and you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us in this way. If you have any questions about security on the Site, you can email SideTour at [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com).

**10.    ****Exclusions**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any personal information collected by SideTour other than personal information collected through the Services. This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to SideTour through the Site or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of the Site, such as comments or bulletin boards (collectively, “Public Areas”), any ideas for new products or modifications to existing products, and other unsolicited submissions (collectively, “Unsolicited Information”). All Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential and SideTour shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, distribute and exploit such Unsolicited Information without limitation or attribution. ****

**11.    ****Privacy Policies of Third Parties**

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information SideTour collects from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether they are customers or hosts on SideTour or throughout the internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. SideTour does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. SideTour is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of other websites on the Internet, even those linked to or from the Site. SideTour encourages you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others. ****

**12.    ****Changes to this Privacy Policy**

The Services may change from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for SideTour to make changes to this Privacy Policy.  We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy, effective upon posting of an updated version of this Privacy Policy on this page of the Site.  You are responsible for reviewing the most recent version of this Privacy Policy and remaining informed about any modifications.

**13.    ****Feedback; Questions**

Please contact us at [info@sidetour.com](mailto:info@sidetour.com) to report any violations of this Privacy Policy or to ask any questions regarding this Privacy Policy.
